mybasis.com 2015-03-19

# Basis Privacy Policy | Basis

**LAST UPDATED** : December 1, 2014

**BASIS Privacy Policy**

Basis has recently been acquired by Intel! Read more [here](http://www.mybasis.com/blog/2014/03/basis-health-tracker-acquired-by-intel/).

At BASIS Science, Inc., our priority is the privacy and security of your personal information. This privacy policy describes the information we collect when you use the www.mybasis.com website, including the store, community and personal dashboard (collectively, the “Site”), our mobile applications, and our devices, such as the Basis Health Tracker (collectively, the “Services”) and how we use and disclose that information.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or sending you an email notification).  We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services to stay informed about our information practices.

Information We Collect 

_Automatically-Collected Information_

When you access or use our Services, we may collect certain information automatically. For example, when you access our website or applications, we log information about your IP address, the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, and the page you visited before navigating to the Site. We also collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Services, including the hardware model, operating system and version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information. We may also use cookies, which are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer through your Web browser. Cookies allow us to enhance and personalize your online browsing and shopping experience. For example, we use cookies to remember the items in your shopping cart, recognize you when you return to the Site, and analyze visitor behavior.

Many browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you are to receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Some of the web pages on the Site and parts of the BASIS Services do require cookies to function correctly, so we recommend that you leave them turned on. However you may delete them after you leave the Site.

We may also collect information using web beacons (also known as “tracking pixels”).  Web beacons are electronic images that may be used in our Services or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and determine whether an email has been opened and acted upon.

We may allow other companies to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet or to provide analytics services. These entities may use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked, and conversion information. This information may be used to analyze and track data or to deliver advertising targeted to your interests on other websites.  For more information about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes, please visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). The use of cookies and web beacons by our partners is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

_Information You Give Us_

We do not collect any personal information about you unless you voluntarily submit the information to us. When you register for our Services, you will be asked to provide certain personal information, such as your name, e-mail address, and date of birth. The BASIS Service asks you to provide certain additional information to help the Services function properly, such as your age, weight, height, and activity level. Finally, to the extent you make purchases from us via our online store, you may be required to submit purchase information, such as your shipping address and credit card account number.

_Information Collected from Your Device, Storage of information_

When you use a Basis Health Tracker device, the device records information about your activity and your body’s response. This data does not include where you are or who you are with, but does include time, heart rate, skin temperature, ambient temperature, galvanic skin response, and accelerometer data. This information resides on your device until you synch the device or otherwise upload it to the Services, at which point it is stored on our servers. The Services analyze this information and run algorithms to calculate personalized measurements, such as number of calories burned, amount of physical activity, and amount of sleep.

You may stop recording information on your device at any time, for any period of time, by not wearing the device. You also may choose not to upload particular data on your device to the Services.

Please note that we may store your information on servers that may be situated in the USA or in other countries that may not be required to adhere to the same level of personal data protection as required in the EU.

How We Use the Information We Collect

We use automatically-collected information to analyze trends, administer the Services, understand how users engage with the Services, and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We may use personal information you provide to deliver the BASIS Service, including for the following purposes:

  * To create and maintain your account.
  * For administration purposes, such as contacting you for reasons related to the BASIS Service for which you have registered (e.g. password reminders, service notifications, etc.) or a submission you have made.
  * To issue invoices, administer accounts, or collect and process payments.
  * To send you e-mails, e-newsletters, personalized offers, or other communications about our products and services in accordance with your communication preferences.

We may use the data uploaded from your BASIS device to provide and improve the BASIS Services, including to provide customer support and to build features, such as leaderboards, which will be available to our community of users.

How We Share the Information We Collect

Information about our customers is an important part of our business, and we use it responsibly. We do not share, sell, rent or otherwise disclose personal information to third parties for promotional purposes. We do share information with our affiliated entities, other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include storage of your data, processing credit card payments, shipping, web analytics, surveys and providing marketing assistance. These service providers have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but are contractually forbidden from using it for other purposes.

We may also share information in response to a court order, when required by law, or to enforce our policies or to protect our or others’ rights, property, or safety.

If we undertake a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, sale of all or a portion of our assets, bankruptcy, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction.  You will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of personal information.

We may share or sell aggregated, de-identified data with third parties, including, but not limited to, for marketing purposes or with research organizations.

The BASIS Service provides you with the ability to share portions of the information you provide or that is collected by your device with third party services, social networks, specific users, and the general public. This data is shared according to your selected privacy choices. Any data you share may become publicly available and could be read, collected, and/or used by third parties, including other users, unknown to us and you. We encourage you to be cautious in determining what you disclose and to whom you disclose it.

Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information such as name and address of minors, and we require users to be at least eighteen (18) years old to use the BASIS Service. If we learn that we have collected children’s personal information without parental consent, we will delete it from our systems.

Links to Other Sites

The Site contains links to other sites that we do not own or control. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies only to information collected by our Services.

Security

We have implemented reasonable security measures in order to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction.

Preferences

As discussed above, you can always choose not to provide certain information, even though it might be needed to take advantage of some of the features of our Services. You also have the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided or removing your information from our database.

E-Mail Communication: To unsubscribe from an email, please follow the instructions in the email you receive.

BASIS Service: To modify personal information such as your name, address and contact information, please login to the service and update your profile.

Marketing: At any time, you may request that we stop using your personal data for marketing purposes e.g. by sending an email to support@mybasis.com.

If you wish to cancel your account, withdraw your consent or request that we no longer use your data to provide you services or that we delete your data contact us at support@mybasis.com.

BASIS Science, Inc.  
1200 Folsom Street  
San Francisco, CA 94103  
support@mybasis.com

Safe Harbor

Basis complies with the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  Basis has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification page, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, Basis commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information.  European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Basis at:

BASIS Science, Inc.  
1200 Folsom Street  
San Francisco, CA 94103  
support@mybasis.com

Basis has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Basis, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints for more information and to file a complaint.
